ort.org 2019-04-24

# Privacy Policy - World ORT

At World ORT we respect the privacy of visitors to our website (www.ort.org). This policy is concerned with how we collect information, what we do with it and what controls you have over your personal information.

## Your Privacy

World ORT is a worldwide charity whose aim is to:

– Work for the advancement of Jewish and non-Jewish people through training and education;

– Provide communities wherever they are, with the skills and knowledge necessary to cope with the complexities and uncertainties of their environment;

– Foster economic self-sufficiency, mobility and a sense of identity through use of state-of-the-art technology;

– Support non-sectarian economic and social development through International Cooperation programs in under-developed parts of the world, with vocational training and the provision of technical assistance.

We take our duty to process your personal information very seriously. This policy explains how we collect, manage, use and protect your personal information.

We may change this document from time to time to reflect the latest view of what we do with your information. Please check back frequently; you will be able to see if changes have been made by the date it was last updated.

Refer to the sections below for more details on how and why we use your personal information:

  1. Who are we?
  2. What personal information we collect and how we use it
  3. Legitimate interests
  4. Sharing your information
  5. Retaining your information
  6. Your details on the web
  7. What are your rights?
  8. How to contact us

## 1\. Who are we?

In this policy references to World ORT, or to ‘ORT’ ‘we’ or ‘us’ are referring to World Ort and World ORT Trust. World Ort has a registered office in Geneva, Switzerland and administrative offices in London and New York. The World Ort Trust is a registered charity in England and Wales, (registered charity number 1042541).

## 2\. What personal information we collect and how we use it

### What we need

ORT is what’s known as the ‘controller’ of the personal information you provide to us. We will usually collect basic personal information about you like your name, postal address, telephone number, email address and your payment details if you are donating to us.

Sometimes we will collect other information about you such as your date of birth, gender and other details. We will be very clear with you that we wish to collect such information, our reason for collecting such information, and we would only do so with your consent.

### Why we need it

We collect your personal information in connection with specific activities, such as campaign updates, newsletter requests, registration or event requests, donations, feedback, competition entries, information you provide in public forums on our sites and applications.

The information is either needed to fulfil your request or to enable us to provide you with a more personalised service. You don’t have to disclose any of this information to browse our site. However, if you choose to withhold requested information, we may not be able to provide you with certain services.

### Our marketing

Sometimes, with your consent, we will process your personal information to provide you with information about our work or our activities that you have requested or are expecting.

On other occasions, we may process personal information when we need to do this to fulfil a contract or where we are required to do this by law or other regulations.

ORT also processes your information when it is in our legitimate interests to do this and when these interests do not override your rights. Those legitimate interests include providing you with information on our services, campaigns, events, newsletter requests, feedback, competitions and other activities. Please see the section on ‘Legitimate Interest’ for more information.

### How we obtain your details

We will also hold information about your details so that we can respect your preferences for being contacted by us.

We collect your personal information in a number of ways:

When you provide it to us directly.

When you provide permission to other organisations to share it with us (including Facebook or Twitter).

When we collect it as you use our websites or apps.

When you have given it to a third party and you have provided permission to pass your information on to us.

From publicly available sources (where possible) to keep your information up to date (e.g. the Post Office’s National Change of Address database).

We combine the information from these sources with the information you provide to us directly.

### Children

If you are under 16 please ensure you obtain your parent/guardian’s consent before sending any personal information to any website or ORT.  We do have activities for those under 16 so we may ask your age. Before taking part please ensure you speak to your parent or guardian.

Please note that we will not knowingly market to or accept orders for goods or services from persons aged under 16 years.

As a parent or guardian, we encourage you to be aware of the activities in which your children are participating, both offline and online. If your children voluntarily disclose information, this may encourage unsolicited messages. We suggest that you discourage your child from providing any information without your consent.

### Anything else?

Wherever possible we try to process the personal information we hold about you in the EEA, but as we are an international organisation that is not always possible. We may need to transfer your information outside the EEA in order to provide you with a service or information. Whenever we transfer information outside the EEA, we ensure that there are security protocols and relevant contract terms in place to protect and secure your personal information. This will be done in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation.

If you would like to change the way you hear from us or no longer wish to receive direct marketing communications from then use the contact form on our ‘Contact Us’ page.

### 3\. Legitimate interests

We have a number of lawful reasons that mean we can use your personal information. One of these is something called ‘legitimate interests’. Broadly speaking Legitimate Interests means we can process your personal information if:

We have a genuine and legitimate reason.

and

We are not harming any of your rights and interests.

Please read the information we have provided in the [‘Legitimate Interest’ policy](https://www.ort.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/World-Ort-Legitimate-Interests.pdf) for more detailed information.

### 4\. Sharing your information

We do not share your information with any other organisations or individuals unless we are when obliged to by law, for purposes of national security, taxation and criminal investigations and in the following instances:

  * If you have agreed that we may do so.
  * When we use other companies to provide services on our behalf, e.g. processing, mailing or delivering orders, answering your questions about services or programmes, sending mail and emails, customer analysis, assessment, when using auditors/advisors or processing credit/debit card payments.
  * To our affiliated charities (Regional fundraising charities such as ORT Uk).
  * If we merge with another organisation to form a new entity, information may be transferred to the new entity.
  * We may disclose aggregate statistics about our site visitors, supporters, customers and sales to describe our services and operations to prospective partners, advertisers and other reputable third parties and for other lawful purposes, but these statistics won’t include any personally identifying information.
  * If we run an event in partnership with other named organisations your details may need to be shared. We will be very clear what will happen to your personal information when you register.

And, we will never sell or rent your personal information to other organisations.

### 5\. Retaining your information

We hold your information only as long as necessary for each reason that we use it. We have provided some examples of the time we will keep your information in this paragraph but you can contact us for more information.

If you decide not to support ORT any more or request that we have no further contact with you, we will keep some basic information in order to avoid sending you unwanted materials in the future and to ensure that we don’t accidentally duplicate information.

If you attend an event, make a donation or provide any financial support, we will keep the purchase information for a period of seven years for accounting purposes.

### 6\. Our cookie Policy – [Read the policy](https://www.ort.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/World-Ort-Cookie-Policy.pdf)

### 7\. What are your rights?

You have a number of rights about how the personal information you provide can be used. These are:

  * Transparency over how we use your personal information (right to be informed).
  * The ability to request a copy of the information we hold about you, which will be provided to you within one month (right of access).
  * Update or amend the information we hold about you if it is wrong (right of rectification).
  * Ask us to stop using your information (right to restrict processing).
  * Ask us to remove your personal information from our records (right to be ‘forgotten’).
  * Object to the processing of your information for marketing purposes (right to object).
  * Obtain and reuse your personal information for your own purposes (right to data portability).
  * Not be subject to a decision when it is based on automated processing (automated decision making and profiling).

If you would like to know more about your rights under the data protection law, you can find out more at the Information Commissioners Office website (UK) or the supervisory body for your country of residence (if in the EEA).

Remember, you can change the way you hear from us or withdraw your permission for us to process your personal information at any time by using the form on our ‘Contact Us’ page.

### 8\. How to contact us

If you wish to talk through anything in our privacy policy, find out more about your rights or obtain a copy of the information we hold about you, please contact us (details at the bottom of this page), we will be happy to help.

If you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal information, you can contact us and we will investigate the matter. If you are not satisfied with our response or believe we are not processing your personal information in accordance with the law you can complain to the local supervisory body, the Information Commissioners Office in the UK, for example.

If you wish to talk to us about anything in the policy or the information we hold about you please contact us:

**CONTACT (LONDON)**

Administrative Office  
126 Albert Street, London, NW1 7NE  
United Kingdom

Telephone: +44 (0)20 7446 8500  
Fax: +44 (0)20 7446 8650  
Email: [wo@ort.org](mailto:wo@ort.org)

**CONTACT (NEW YORK)**

Representative Office  
1745 Broadway, 17th floor  
New York, 10019, USA

Telephone: +1 212.519.9839  
Fax: +1 212.519.9804  
Email: [wony@ort.org](mailto:wony@ort.org)

**CONTACT (GENEVA)**

Registered Office  
1 rue de Varembé  
1211 Geneva 20  
Switzerland

Email: [office@ortsuisse.org](mailto:office@ortsuisse.org)

This document was last updated: May 2018
